Ethers js is one of the most popular JavaScript based tooling kits,
Ethers.js 是最流行的 JavaScript 工具包之一
that allows us to interact with different blockchains
它能让我们与不同的区块链进行交互
and has all these rappers that make all these API calls
并且有许多封装函数可以进行 API 调用
and do all these things with Aetherium, and polygon and avalanche and any EVM compatible chain.
它可以在以太坊，Polygon，Avalanche 等一切兼容 EVM 的区块链上使用
The other incredibly popular package
还有一个同样受欢迎的包
that does the same thing is going to be web three.js.
名字是 web3.js 它也可以做到前面说到的那些事
And you've probably heard about this
你可能之前就听说过这个东西
and you'll probably see it a little bit more throughout this course and throughout your web three journey.
并且在本课程和你的 Web3 之旅中，你可能会经常见到它
The reason that we're using ethers is that
我们使用 ethers 的原因是
ethers is the main tool that powers the hard hat environment
ethers 是支撑 Hardhat 环境的主要工具
and I really enjoy it myself.
而且我个人也非常喜欢使用
And remember, if you ever get lost with any of this, you can always come back to their documentation
一旦你有什么搞不明白的，可以随时查看他们的文档
to install it. As you can see here,
要安装它，可以看这里
you can just run npm install ethers,
你只需要运行 "npm install ethers"
we're just going to do yarn, add ethers.
但我们的做法是 "yarn add ethers"
And now you should see in your package json,
现在你应该就能在 package.json 里看到
we now have ethers added in here. Awesome.
我们已经把 ethers 添加到了这里，很好
Now back in our code, we're going to import ethers into our deployed.js script
现在回到我们的代码，我们要把 ethers 导入进脚本 deploy.js
so that we can use all the wonderful tools that comes with
这样我们就能够使用里面所有的奇妙工具了
so we'll say const ethers equals require ethers.
我们输入 "const ethers = require("ethers")"
For those of you doing the TypeScript edition of this course,
如果你使用的是 TypeScript
this will be import instead of require
那这里就不是 "require" 而是 "import"
now that we have ethers in here, we can create our provider object in our main function.
现在这里已经有了 ethers ，可以为我们的 main 函数创建 provider 对象了
The reason we we pull ethers outside of the main function
我们把 ethers 放到 main 函数之外的原因是
is because we do want to pull our package into our script. Before we call main,
我们想在调用 main 函数之前就把这个包导入进脚本中
we want to make sure all of this is done first.
我们要确保这件事首先完成
So you'll see this is kind of the the normal setup of our scripts.
现在你看到的这些就是我们脚本的一般配置
At the top, we import any dependencies or external packages,
在顶部，我们先把依赖库或外部包都导入进来
we'll have our main function, and then we'll call our main function at the bottom.
我们还会有一个 main 函数，并且我们会在底部调用这个 main 函数
const is a keyword similar to let
"const" 是一个与 "let" 类似的关键字
the const keyword makes it so that ethers can't be changed.
"const" 关键字能够使得 "ethers" 无法被更改
So we can't change this. Our ethers variable, anytime we use const
所以一旦我们使用了 "const" 就再也不能更改 "ethers" 这个变量了
require is a function for us to import the ethers package.
而 "require" 是一个函数，它负责导入 ethers 包
Now remix does all this behind the scenes.
Remix 把所有事都放到了幕后完成
But the way we're going to do it in our code here
但我们需要在我们的代码这里完成
is we're going to say const provider equals new ethers dot providers dot JSON RPC provider.
我们要输入 "const provider = new ethers.providers.JsonRpcProvider"
And then we're going to pass this string as our provider.
然后我们要将这个字符串作为我们的 provider
So we're saying hey, we're going to connect to this URL right here.
我们写的意思就是，嘿，我们要连接到这个 URL 去
Awesome. So this is the way that our script is going to connect to our blockchain, our local blockchain.
非常好，这就是我们的脚本连接到区块链的方法，本地区块链
Now let's get an actual wallet here.
现在让我们获得一个钱包
With a private key and a balance and everything,
它具有私钥和余额以及所有其他必要的东西
we can see all of our wallets and private keys in our ganache here.
可以看到我们所有的钱包和私钥都在 Ganache 这里
So the way to get this set up is we can say
获取钱包的具体方法是
const. Wallet equals new ethers dot wallet.
"const wallet = new ethers.Wallet()"
And this wallet function takes in a couple of input parameters, like a private key, and a provider,
这个 "Wallet" 函数需要接收几个参数，比如私钥和 provider
the private key will go to Kenosha
获得私钥的方法是来到 Ganache 这里
and just choose one of these private keys.
从这些私钥中选择其中一个
And we're going to paste this right into our code.
我们要把它粘贴到我们的代码里
And then we're gonna do comma provider and save that.
接着是逗号 "provider"，并且保存
Now pasting your private key directly into your code is a huge nono.
注意，直接把私钥粘贴进你的代码里其实是一个大忌
And we're going to learn how to avoid this in the future.
之后我们会学习如何避免这一点
It's okay right now, since we're just using one of the ganache private keys,
不过现在没事，因为我们用的只是 Ganache 上的私钥
and you have no risk of having any money associated with this account.
所以并不存在任何与此账户关联的资金风险
These two lines alone give us everything that we need to interact with smart contract,
这两行代码就足以提供我们与智能合约交互所需要的一切。
they give us our connection to the blockchain,
它们提供了我们与区块链的连接
and they give us a wallet with a private key
并提供了一个带有私钥的钱包
so we can sign different transactions.
以使我们可以对不同的交易进行签名
If you remember back to our blockchain basics section.
如果你还记得我们的“区块链基础部分”
This is the private key that we're using to sign all of our transactions to encrypt our transactions.
这个就是我们用来签署和加密我们交易的私钥
Now that we have a provider and a wallet,
现在我们有了 provider 和 钱包
let's go ahead and grab our contract objects from these two files here.
让我们继续从这两个文件中获取我们的合约对象
In order to deploy our contract,
为了部署我们的合约
we're gonna need the ABI and we're going to need the binary compiled code of the contract.
我们需要智能合约的 ABI 以及编译后的二进制代码
So we're going to need to read from these two files
所以我们需要读取这两个文件的内容
to read from these two files, we're going to need to use a package called Fs.
为了读取这两个文件，我们需要使用一个叫做 "fs" 的包
So back at the top, we're gonna do const Fs equals require Fs extra
回到代码顶部，定义 "const fs = require("fs-extra")"
I autosave, all the time, you'll see like, I'll do something
在你看来我几乎是一直在自动保存，每次我做完一些事
and then my white dot will go away a lot.
我的小白点就会消失
It's because my fingers have a habit of pretty much anytime I stop typing I save
这是因为我有个习惯，每当我停止输入的时候我就会保存一下
so so please remember to save early and often,
所以请记得经常保存，尽早保存
this Fs extra should come directly with your node project.
这个 "fs-extra" 应该是随着你的 "Node(.js)" 项目直接提供的
But if not, you can always add it with yarn, add Fs extra,
但如果没有，你总可以通过 "yarn add fs-extra" 添加它
and you should see it in our package dot JSON.
然后你应该就能在 "package.json" 文件中看到它
Now we can get the ABI and the binary,
现在我们就可以获取 ABI 和二进制文件了
we can say const, abi equals Fs dot read file sync,
输入 "const abi = fs.readFileSync()"
which means we're going to synchronously read from this file,
这意味着我们将同步读取这个文件
we could do it asynchronously. But we want to wait for this file to get done.
我们可以采用异步处理，但这里我们想等待文件读取完成
So we're gonna say read file sync.
所以我们使用的是 "readFileSync"
And depending on your VS code, if you scroll over,
取决于你是否使用 VS Code，如果你悬停鼠标
you might even get some information about this function popup like this, which can be really helpful,
可能会看到弹出这么一个显示函数信息的窗口，这个东西很有用
we can see that we need the path for the file we want to read.
可以看到，我们需要提供想要读取的文件所在的路径("path")
And then any options as well
以及一些其他选项
path the file that we want to read the at the ABI located at dot slash simple storage, underscore soul underscore
simple storage dot AVI and then we're going to do a comma of U
T, F eight is UTF. Eight is the encoding that we do for this
file here. Don't worry too much about what that means for now.
So we need the ABI. And we also need the binary, which is in
this second file. Simple Storage underscore soul underscore
simple storage dot bin. So we're gonna say const binary equals Fs
dot read file sync. We're gonna give it the path Hear, which is
going to be dot slash, simple storage soul, simple storage dot
bin, and then the encoding option, which again is going to
be, and it should look like this. Now that we have the
binary, we have the ABI, we can create something called a
contract factory, which is not to be confused with the factory
pattern in ethers. A contract factory is just an object that
you can use to deploy contracts. So we're gonna say const,
contract factory equals new ethers dot contract, factory.
And we're going to pass it, the API binary. And the wallet, we
pass the ABI so that our code knows how to interact with the
contract the binary, obviously, because this is the main
compiled code in our wallet so that we have a private key we
can use to sign deploying this contract, then I usually like to
write a little console dot log, saying something like deploying
these wait. And we can actually deploy this contract with ethers
by doing const. Contract equals await, contract factory dot
deploy. Now, this is the first time we've seen this await
keyword and you can only use the await keyword inside of an async
function. The reason we want this await keyword we're telling
our code to stop here, wait for contract to deploy. And this
await keyword means that this will resolve the promise
contract in this contract factory dot deploy with the
await here returns a contract object. So now I could do
something like console dot log contract. Let's see what happens
when we run this code node deploy dot j s, we scroll up, we
see deploying, please wait. And then we see this massive object
that gets printed out. This is the contract object that we just
deployed. And in fact, if we go over to our ganache, we can see
that the address that we're used for our wallet has a little bit
less balance and has a transaction count of one. If we
were working with truffle, we'd be able to see the contracts
here we're working with hard hat, so you won't be able to see
the contracts in here. But if you go to transactions, we can
indeed see the transaction that we just created. This is similar
to ether scan. But for our local blockchain, we can see the
sender address, the creation address, the value, gas price,
all this stuff associated with this contract. You can also see
the different blocks. Since we've only made one transaction
only one block has been mined. And this is awesome. We have all
this other stuff associated with it. Great job. You just deployed
a contract to your own local blockchain with ethers. Jas.
This is fantastic, Awesome work. Now let me show you what happens